THARAN BALA

Full Stack Developer

Milwaukee, Wisconsin | tharanbala33@gmail.com | (414) 243-5462 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/tharan-bala/

SUMMARY

With over three years of experience in Full Stack Development, I have utilized Python, ReactJS, Data Science and Cloud technologies to successfully execute numerous projects, delivering results that have enhanced business performance. I am recognized as a proficient decision-maker, a reliable team leader, and possess strong communication skills.

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Science

Aug2022-May2024

University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee, Milwaukee, Wisconsin

GPA:3.5/4

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

Aug2016-Aug2020

Sri Ramakrishna Engineering College, Coimbatore, India

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee

Present

Help Desk Chatbot

• Help Desk chatbot is a chat bot application used as one of the methods of contact for the UWM IT Help Desk. Building the initial application model with Django, Rasa framework and using ReactJs, Typescript.

Sri Ramakrishna Engineering College

Jan2019-May2019

Way Map

• Implemented the application using Unity and Blender focusing on C# and unit tested the application.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages Python (Flask, Django, Pandas, NumPy), Next.js, ReactJs, Typescript, HTML5, Tailwind CSS, Git

Database SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Cloud Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

University of Wisconsin Milwaukee - IT Help Desk

Supervisor Feb2023-Present

• Promoted to Supervisor from consultant in 3 months. Oversaw the efficient operation of the Help Desk.

Consultant Nov2022-Feb2023

- Served as primary contact point for addressing all IT support requirements for UWM.
- Provided end users technical assistance and troubleshooted issues related to UWM account, software.

Seminaut Inc., San Marcos, Texas

Full Stack Engineer Internship

Jun2023-Aug2023

• Utilized Flask framework to create REST APIs and ReactJs, Typescript to develop reusable models. Engaged in teamwork with fellow interns and maintained code synchronization through Git version.

Payoda Technologies Pvt Ltd, Coimbatore, India

Software Developer

Aug2019-Feb2022

- Cloth Prediction using Deep Learning Algorithms The Flask and ReactJs based dashboard are to predict the Cloth stitch type, stitch pattern, and diameter. Hosted the application and configured EC2 on AWS. May2021-Feb2022
- Smart Call Centre The purpose of this application is to help Customer Care to handle their customers with ease. Used technologies such as Flask, Vue.js, NLP to develop the application for Verizon.

 Feb2021-May2021
- MyTheo: Real Estate Application MyTheo is a Real Estate Client with real estate agencies all over the USA with headquarters in California. Incorporated technologies such as Ruby on Rails, HAML, SCSS and Google Street view.

Feb2020-Feb2021

Alternative Soft - It is a portfolio construction software. It has simplified the funds selection and portfolio construction
process for institutional investors. Involved in development using technologies such as Dot Net, ReactJs, Microservices
and SQL.
 Aug2019-Feb2020